University Towers Investment Club; Records ua814
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
University Towers Investment Club Records
1965-1991
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
University Towers Investment Club
ua814
1 cubic ft.
The collection includes the records of the University Towers Investment Club ranging from 1965 to 1991. The records detail the club's the investment activities, politics, and the financial status of the club.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to this collection is unrestricted.
Arrangement
Collection was maintained in the original order after it was transferred.
Biographical / Historical
The University Towers Investment Club was a faculty club founded in 1962. The club's purpose was to pool member's money together to make greater investments in the stock market. The club was limited to about 15 members when it was first was founded and steadily grew overtime. Club membership was restrictive and potential members had to apply to become a member. Meetings were held once a month to discuss the club's investments. Membership increased even greater when the club was merged with the Albany Towers Investing Club in 1973.The club amassed an investment portfolio of about 35,000 dollars, by investing in companies such as, Disney, AT&T, Pan American World Airways, and John Deere.
Content Description
Accessioned along with Provost and Graduate Studies materials. The collection contains records from the University Towers Investment Club. Records include documents such as memos, investment portfolios, meeting notifications, meeting records, correspondence between club leaders and members, financial records of the club, and tax statements.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Discovered as part of Provost and Graduate Studies materials in 2016 and moved to separate collection. Sorrell Chesin has arranged the transfer of materials in the past, so it is possible that he was responsible for these records as well.
UAlbany Faculty & Alumni Papers; Stock market.; Investment tax credit; Stock Market Crash, 1987
- Correspondance, 1972-1975 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Meeting Notices, 1970-1975 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Monthly Statements, 1973-1975 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Articles of Agreement, 1969-1975 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Club Receipts, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Meeting Notices, 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Club Attendance and Treasurer Records, 1968-1970 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Investor Manual, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Bank and Finanical Records, 1969-1973 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Memos, 1967-1975 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Memos, 1968-1974 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Tax Records, 1968-1973 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Investment Portfolios, 1967-1973 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Memos, 1987-1991 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Investment Portfolios, 1987-1991 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Data Channel, 1987 October (Box 2, Folder 5)